在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime
擎天柱回到了成为领袖之前的状态：\N奥利安・派克斯
Optimus has reverted to his pre-Prime state: Orion Pax.
钥匙芯片！它是做什么用的？
The Key-card! What does it do?
用来启动魔力神球
It grants access to Vector Sigma
它是一种神秘力量的古老源泉
an ancient source of mystical power.
在塞博特恩
On Cybertron.
当我们在塞博特恩内战中取得优势之时 我们占领了铁堡的档案馆
When we stormed the Iacon Hall of Records in the winning days of the war for Cybertron
从那里得到了一些高度机密文件
we acquired highly classified files
我们无法破译
which we were not able to decipher.
是虎子！
It's 'Cons!
他们又闯进了两个月前他们袭击过的军用实验室
And they're busting into the same military research lab they hit two months ago.
我们让他们造好太空桥
We let them finish building their Space-bridge.
为什么？
Why?
好让我们去接管它
So we can commandeer it.
用它把我送到塞博特恩去
And use it to send me to Cybertron.
但我却没在船上看到他
I have not seen him aboard the ship.
红蜘蛛指挥官已经牺牲了
Commander Starscream is dead.
擎天柱？
Optimus Prime?!
别这样！
Please!
我没有恶意！
I mean no harm!
哦！那你在这里做什么？！
Oh! Then what are you doing here?!
为威震天陛下进行调查
Research. For Lord Megatron.
你在拿我寻开心吗？
Is this some kind of joke?
我…不明白
I... do not understand.
还有你为什么叫我擎天柱？
And why did you call me "Optimus Prime"?
为什么不能叫？
Why wouldn't I?
因为我的名字是奥里安・派克斯
Because my name is Orion Pax.
我离当领袖还差得远呢
I am far from being a Prime.
你让我想起了一个老相识 就是这样
You reminded me of someone I once knew. That's all.
你是红蜘蛛
You are Starscream.
…是的
...Yes.
威震天陛下告诉我你已经…光荣捐躯了
Lord Megatron told me you had been... terminated.
威震天陛下说话一向不太靠谱
Lord Megatron says many things, only some of which are true.
你…不会是在暗示我们的首领说谎吧？
You... do not suggest that our leader would speak falsehoods?
你不会真的被蒙在鼓里了吧？
You truly are being kept in the dark, aren't you?
你的话着实令我费解 红蜘蛛
You speak in many riddles, Starscream.
请告诉我你都知道些什么
Please, tell me what it is that you know.
作为回报…
And in return...
投降吧！红蜘蛛！
Starscream! Surrender!
别开枪！
Hold your fire!
老实呆在实验室里
Remain in the lab.
但是我…
But I...
这是威震天陛下的命令
Lord Megatron's orders.
拉斐尔！实验对象都准备好了么？
Rafael! Is the test subject ready?
完毕！
Check!
远程GPS已启动
Long-range GPS activated.
不知二次校准能否将其成功地延伸至环陆桥范围
I have doubts whether my recalibrations have successfully  extended Ground-bridge range.
只有一种方法来验证
But there's only one way to find out.
来吧！
Come on!
这只不过是首次测试
It was just the first try...
不 拉斐尔 这太蠢了
No, Rafael. It was pure folly.
这是绝望下的荒唐之举
A misguided act of desperation.
掌握太空桥工程需要花费一辈子的时间
It takes eons to master Space-bridge engineering.
没有人比霸天虎更了解它…
And no one is more accomplished than the Decepticons...
你知道么 这就像在体育课上爬绳子
You know, there is this thing in gym class where you have to climb a rope.
要一直爬到上面
All the way to the ceiling.
这真的很难
It's really hard.
我从未成功过
And I've never been able to do it.
不过…
But...
当我告诉小蜂的时候
When I told Bee about it
他相信我能行
he believed in me.
在鼓励之下 我反复地练习
Which made me practice a ton.
最终 仅仅几周之后
Finally, just a couple of weeks ago
我成功地爬上去了
I made it! To the top.
这和体育课有关系么？
What does any of this have to do with gym class?!
我…我只是…
I... I was just...
让你一个人静静吧
I'll give you some alone time.
擎天柱…我很抱歉
Optimus... I am so sorry.
奥利安
Orion.
我对最近的骚动表示抱歉
I am so sorry for the recent commotion.
你没有受伤吧？
You weren't in any way harmed, were you?
没有 威震天陛下
No, Lord Megatron.
但你为什么对我说红蜘蛛死了？
But why did you tell me Starscream was dead?
因为他不再追寻我们的事业了
Because he is dead to our cause.
红蜘蛛曾是我最信任的副官
Starscream was my most trusted lieutenant.
直到他成为叛徒 加入了汽车人
Until he turned traitor and joined the Autobots.
这是我经历过的最刻骨铭心的背叛
Never have I witnessed a more profound act of deceit.
他没对你说什么蛊惑人心的言论吧？
He did not do or say anything troubling to you?
没有
No.
这就好
Good.
最好忘记这些琐事
Perhaps it's best to forget the entire incident
回到工作上吧
and return to your project.
遵命 我的陛下
As you wish, my Lord.
奥利安永远都不会懂得欺骗的艺术
Orion was never very adept at the art of deception.
我犯了一个错误 没能当机立断地宰了红蜘蛛
I made a mistake not terminating Starscream when I had the opportunity.
这是我绝不会再犯的错误！
A mistake I do not intend to make again!
没有能量的迹象
No sign of energon spikes.
阿尔茜和小蜂找到太空桥了么？
Arcee or Bee find the Space-bridge?
他们还没有什么消息
They haven't yet reported back.
救护车 你还好么？
Ratchet. You alright?
嗯？我很好！
Hm? Yes!
好 我们进行下一步行动
Yes. Let's just get you to the next quadrant.
这是什么？
What is it?
一个高频信号
A high-frequency signal.
内含一个加密的信息
With an embedded message!
…给我的
... for me.
是擎天柱？
Optimus?
是红蜘蛛
Starscream.
我得到了关于你们领袖的情报
"I have obtained information regarding your Leader.
带上医疗箱 一个人来
Bring medical kit. Come alone".
我告诉过你要一个人来！
I told you to come alone!
我们什么时候开始非得听你的了？
And since when do we listen to you?
擎天柱在哪儿？
Where is Optimus?
把我修好 或许我会告诉你
Patch me up and perhaps I'll tell you.
发发慈悲吧 我的能量在泄漏！
Have sympathy. I'm leaking here!
那你就快说
Then I suggest that you speak quickly!
擎天柱有没有受到伤害？！
Has Optimus been harmed in any way?!
他很好 非常好！
He's fine. Fine!
你没看见我才是被伤害的那一个么？
Can't you see I'm the one who's been harmed?
他在哪儿？！
Where is he?!
那你认为他还能在哪儿？！
Where do you think?!
当然在威震天的战舰上！
He's on Megatron's warship!
具体位置呢？
Which is located Where?
哼…啊 现在谁知道
Ha... ha. Now, who knows?
那是艘飞船！会动！
It's a ship! It moves.
我追踪了它几个月换来的只有这一身的枪子
It took me months to track only to get fired upon.
你不会自讨麻烦叫我来的
You wouldn't go to the trouble of calling me here
除非你有可以用来交换的情报
unless you had information to trade.
…真正的情报！
... real information!
很好…
Very well...
你挚爱的领袖丧失了自我意识
Your beloved Leader may have lost his senses.
他现在是奥利安・派克斯
He goes by the name "Orion Pax" now.
看起来威震天让他相信自己成了一个霸天虎！
And it seems Megatron has led him to believe he's a Decepticon.
说些我们不知道的吧
Tell us something we don't know.
什么？！
What?!
你们怎么知道这些的？！
How could you possibly know that?!
我们在浪费时间
We are wasting our time.
等等！这是我知道的全部了！真的！
Wait. That's all I have! Really!
你不能把我扔在这里！
You can't just leave me like this!
除非你知道威震天把他的太空桥藏在何处
Unless you know where Megatron is hiding his Space-bridge
不然你就留在这里等着生锈吧
you can stay here and rust.
太空桥…
Space-bridge...
你的意思是说\N他们在没有我指导的情况下完成了？！
Do you mean to tell me that they actually finished building it without my supervision?!
…这才是最戳我痛处的地方 医生
... it hurts most right here, Doctor.
霸天虎的太空桥就在这里
The Decepticons' Space-bridge is located right here.
在一个能量矿的深处
Deep within an Energon mine.
紧靠原始能量供给 很聪明
Adjacent to a raw fuel supply. Clever.
哪里来的消息
What's our intel?
一个…可靠的来源
A... reliable source.
那么！我们达成共识了么？
So! Do we have a consensus?
你知道人类能在那里的大气层下呼吸么？
Do we know if people can even breathe your atmosphere?
这个我能帮杰克
I'll back Jack up.
搞到最先进的宇航服
Completely, state of the art.
我在国家航天局有熟人
I still have connections at NASA.
这太危险了
It's too dangerous.
妈妈 我知道这很困难
Mom. I know that this is hard.
但擎天柱冒着生命危险来拯救我们的星球
But Optimus risked his life to save our planet.
他甚至不是人类 我们欠他的
And he's not even human. We owe it to him.
杰克可能是唯一能做到的人 琼
Jack may be the only one who can do this, June.
但不要误会 我不会让杰克孤身前往的
But I don't want you to think for one moment that I'll allow him to travel unchaperoned.
不是每个人都注定平凡一生
Not everyone is destined for an ordinary life.
擎天柱以前也不过是奥利安・派克斯
Optimus Prime was once Orion Pax, after all.
小时候你一直希望能当个宇航员
When you were little, you always wanted to be an astronaut.
好吧 擎天柱
Okay. "Optimus Prime".
擎天柱 汽车人侵略者的匪首
"Optimus Prime. Leader of the Autobot invaders."
红蜘蛛看到我时想到了他？
I reminded Starscream of him?
而威震天陛下说救护车才是汽车人的领袖
And Lord Megatron said Ratchet was the Autobot leader.
…有人在说谎
... someone is not telling the truth.
我们将用环陆桥到达能量矿
We will ground-bridge directly in to the energon mine
杀出一条通往控制室的路
and make our way to the Space-bridge chamber
扫清遇到的一切霸天虎障碍
neutralize any Decepticon forces we encounter.
一旦我们控制了太空桥
Once we secure the Space-bridge
就叫杰克过来
we'll send for Jack.
行动必须绝对隐秘
Stealth must be an absolute priority.
我们很可能寡不敌众
We will most certainly be outnumbered
如果有一个霸天虎向战舰报了信…
and if any Decepticon should transmit an alert to their warship...
就会变成四百比一的局面
The odds become four hundred to one.
就这一点而言
Scrambling communications upon entry
干扰通讯系统会为我们的行动提高胜算
will certainly provide an edge in this regard.
占领太空桥还不是最难的
Taking the Bridge is the easy part.
你们三个还要撑足够长的时间
You three need to hold it long enough for Jack and me
直到我和杰克从塞博特恩回来
to get to Cybertron and back.
拉斐尔在体育课上能爬到绳子的顶端 我们也能行
Rafael climbed to the top of the rope in gym class - we can do this.
这和体育课有关系吗？
What does gym class has to do with anything?
如果救护车要搞突袭
And if Ratchet gets to go on a commando raid
我也去
I'm going too.
神子 你能帮助拉斐尔操作我们的环陆桥
Miko. You will help Rafael operate our Ground-bridge
以及管理通信枢纽
and manage the communications hub.
不能去塞博特恩！
Can't go to Cybertron.
又不能占领霸天虎的太空桥！
Can't storm the Decepticon Space-bridge!
达比护士随时待命以应对紧急状况
And nurse Darby will stand-by in case of emergency.
孩子？
Son?
该整装出发了
It's time to suit up.
无异常
Clear.
总部！这里是太空桥控制中心
Command! This is Space-bridge control.
我们被袭击了！
We are under attack!
总部！你们收…？
Command! Do you copy...
下去吧
Going down.
我的火种源啊
By the Allspark!
谢了 红蜘蛛
Thank you, Starscream.
除了他还有谁
Who else would it be?
工程学上的杰作…
A masterpiece of engineering...
能操作吗？
Operational?
能
Fully.
该区域已经占领
Perimeter secured.
现在是最可怕的部分
Now the scary part.
我关闭了干扰器来保持通信以便完成任务
I'm shutting down the scrambler in order to contact base and maintain communications through the remainder of the mission.
突击小队呼叫基地
Strike team to base.
目标已得手
Objective secured.
该你上场了
That’s your cue.
给我带个纪念品回来
Bring me back a souvenir.
那个…你如果要去洗手间可怎么办？
Sooo... what happens when you have to go to the bathroom?
注意安全 孩子
Safe journey, son.
放心…去吧
Just... go already.
擎天柱需要你
Optimus needs you.
锁定塞博特恩
Locking onto Cybertron.
准备好了么？
You ready?
开始吧
Let's do this.
为避免信息延迟我会一直让太空桥保持开启
I'll leave the Space-bridge portal open in order to eliminate any communication lag over the great distance.
也为了你们在回来的时候更容易定位
And make it easier for you to locate when you're ready to return.
容易定位？
Easier to locate?
你不是要用太空桥把我们直接送到魔力神球那里吗？
You're not bridging us straight to the Big V?
魔力神球的真实位置早就被神话跟谣传歪曲了 杰克
Vector Sigma's true location is shrouded in myth and rumour, Jack.
传说领袖之路会通向那里
It is said that the path of the Primes leads there.
我们要坚信擎天柱会引导你的
We must be confident that Optimus will guide you.
别担心 太空桥和环陆桥没什么大的区别
Don't worry. Space-bridging is just like Ground-bridging.
就是稍微有点刺激
Just a little more intense!
我…我真不敢相信
I... I can't believe it!
我竟然在另一个星球上
I am actually on another planet.
阿尔茜 这太难以置信了！
Arcee, this is incredible!
阿尔茜？
Arcee?
我不想让你看到我的家乡是这番景象
This isn't how I wanted you to see my home.
我…我很抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
在战争的迷雾中我们只能看到下一个任务
In the fog of war it is hard to see beyond the next leg of the mission
或者下一场战斗 难有远见卓识
or the next punch in the fight.
我们竭尽全力只为挽救塞博特恩
We did everything to save Cybertron.
当迷雾散去时…
But when the fog finally lifted...
已经剩不下什么可挽救的了
There wasn't much left to save.
阿尔茜！杰克！你收到了么？
Arcee! Jack! Do you copy?
救护车 我们在塞博特恩上
Roger. We're on Cybertron.
- 好哇！\N- 呀哈！
- Yes!\N- Woo-hoo!
感谢上帝！
Oh, thank goodness!
别只顾着观光 呃？
Just keep the sightseeing to a minimum, huh.
没错 我们不知道要走5公里还是500公里
Indeed. We don't know if your journey ahead is 5 kliks or 5000.
明白
Understood.
我们出发吧
We're out.
好吧 救护车说钥匙芯片会引导我 但是…
Okay. Ratchet said the Card would guide us, but...
我不知道如何 或是怎样去…
I don't see how or what I'm supposed to...
就去那边
There you go.
这得好一阵子呢
This could be awhile.
太空桥控制中心 你收到了吗？
Space-Bridge Control, do you read me?
太空桥控制中心 我是打击
Space-bridge control, this is Breakdown.
你没有按时汇报情况
Your status report is overdue.
糟了
Scrap.
隔板 别 他会认出你的声音
Bulkhead, no! He'll recognize your voice.
我能把频率变低
I can make it lower.
或是调高呢?
Higher?
他也会认出我的
He would recognize mine as well.
回话 太空桥控制中心！
Come in, Space-bridge Control!
别逼我下去爆了你的气缸
Don't make me come down and dent some engine blocks.
有人得说点什么 要快！
Somebody say something, pronto!
拉斐尔！让福勒探员上
Rafael! Patch in Agent Fowler.
你有一微循环的时间来报告 不然…
You have one nanocycle to respond or!..
这里是太空桥控制中心 一切正常
This is Space-bridge Control. Situation normal.
正常？你确定？
Normal? You sure about that?
我们就是…校准了一下系统 我们还…
We were just... calibrating the subsystems and we, uh
呃 有点小问题 但现在好了
had a surge, but it's fine now.
你那边好么？
How are you?
呃 嗯…再好不过了！
Er, erm... Never better!
我知道在下面干活不容易
I know it’s thankless down there.
好好干吧
Keep up the good work. Huh?
我们会的 通话结束
Will do. Control out.
为什么霸天虎档案馆的加密如此复杂
Why would the Decepticon archive be so heavily encrypted?
我怎么可能是擎天柱？
How could I possibly be "Optimus Prime"?
就算是我们层层加密也无法让他远离真相
Even our encryptions couldn't keep him from the truth!
奥利安还有许多任务 他会坚持到底的！
Orion has much to accomplish and he will stay the course!
哪怕我得给他施加巨大的痛苦也要完成铁堡计划！
Even if I must inflict great pain to ensure the completion of project "Iacon"!
这边走
That way.
去卡隆？
Toward Kaon?
霸天虎的首都 好极了
The Decepticon capital. Swell.
我们从这里开始步行
We're on foot from here.
我不想让引擎声招来不必要的注意
Don’t want engine noise to attract the wrong kind of attention.
虎子？
'Cons?
害虫
Vermin.
这边走
This way.